are not safe either. So this world that we live in, this world in which every conversation has the potential to devolve into an argument, where our politicians can't speak to one another and where even the most trivial of issues have someone fighting both passionately for it and against it, it's not normal. Pew Research did a study of 10,000 American adults, and they found that at this moment, we are more polarized, we are more divided, than we ever have been in history. We're less likely to compromise, which means we're not listening to each other. And we make decisions about where to live, who to marry and even who our friends are going to be, based on what we already believe. Again, that means we're not listening to each other. A conversation requires a balance between talking and listening, and somewhere along the way, we lost that balance. Now, part of that is due to technology. The smartphones that you all either have in your hands or close enough that you could grab them really quickly. According to Pew Research, about a third of American teenagers send more than a hundred texts a day. And many of them, almost most of them, are more likely to text their friends than they are to talk to them face to face. There's this great piece in The Atlantic. It was written by a high school teacher named Paul Barnwell. And he gave his kids a communication project. He wanted to teach them how to speak on a specific subject without using notes. And he said this: "I came to realize..." (Laughter) "I came to realize that conversational competence might be the single most overlooked skill we fail to teach. Kids spend hours each day engaging with ideas and each other through screens, but rarely do they have an opportunity to hone their interpersonal communications skills. It might sound like a funny question, but we have to ask ourselves: Is there any 21st-century skill more important than being able to sustain coherent, confident conversation?" Now, I make my living talking to people: Nobel Prize winners, truck drivers, billionaires, kindergarten teachers, heads of state, plumbers. I talk to people that I like. I talk to people that I don't like. I talk to some people that I disagree with deeply on a personal level. But I still have a great conversation with them. So I'd like to spend the next 10 minutes or so teaching you how to talk and how to listen. Many of you have already heard a lot of advice on this, things like look the person in the eye, think of interesting topics to discuss in advance, look, nod and smile to show that you're paying attention, repeat back what you just heard or summarize it.
no son seguros tampoco. Así que este mundo en el que vivimos, este mundo en el que cada conversación tiene el potencial de derivar en una discusión donde los políticos no pueden hablarse entre sí y donde incluso el más trivial de los temas tiene a uno debatiendo intensamente en pro y a otro en contra. Eso no es normal. Pew Research hizo un estudio de 10 000 adultos de EE.UU. y descubrió que hoy, estamos más polarizados, estamos más divididos que nunca en la historia. Somos menos propensos a conectar, lo que significa que no escuchamos al resto. Y, tomamos decisiones sobre dónde vivir, con quién vivir e incluso quiénes serán nuestros amigos, con base en lo que ya creemos. Una vez más, eso significa que no escuchamos al resto. Una conversación requiere un equilibrio entre hablar y escuchar, y en algún lugar del camino, perdimos ese equilibrio. Ahora, en parte se debe a la tecnología. A los móviles que todos tienen ya sea en sus manos o lo bastante cerca para usarlos rápidamente. Según Pew Research, cerca de 1/3 de jóvenes en EE.UU. envían más de 100 SMS al día. Y muchos de ellos, en su mayoría, son para escribir a sus amigos que para conversar personalmente. Hay un gran artículo en The Atlantic. escrito por el profesor de secundaria, Paul Barnwell. Él asignó a sus niños una tarea de lenguaje. Quería enseñarles a hablar sobre un tema específico sin usar notas. Y dijo esto: "Me di cuenta de que..." (Risas) "Me di cuenta de que la competencia verbal puede ser la única capacidad más ignorada que fracasamos en enseñar. Los chicos pasan horas relacionándose entre sí con ideas a través de pantallas, pero raramente tienen una oportunidad para afinar habilidades de comunicación interpersonal. Puede sonar a pregunta tonta, pero tenemos que preguntarnos: ¿Hay alguna capacidad en el siglo XXI más importante que poder sostener una conversación coherente y firme?". Yo me gano la vida conversando con la gente: ganadores del Premio Nobel, conductores, multimillonarios, profesores de pre-escolar, jefes de estado, plomeros. Converso con gente que me agrada. Y con gente que no me agrada. Converso a una profundidad personal con gente que estoy en desacuerdo Pero aun así tengo una gran conversación con ellos. Así que me gustaría pasar los próximos 10 minutos enseñándoles a conversar y a escuchar. Muchos ya han escuchado varios consejos sobre esto, cosas como mirar a la gente a los ojos, pensar en temas interesantes para discutir con anticipación, mirar, asentir y sonreír para mostrar que prestan atención, repetir justo lo escuchado o resumirlo.
So I want you to forget all of that. It is crap.
Así que, quiero que olviden todo eso. Es una estupidez.
(Laughter) There is no reason to learn how to show you're paying attention if you are in fact paying attention.
(Risas) No hay razón para aprender a mostrar que se presta atención si de hecho se está prestando atención.
(Laughter) (Applause) Now, I actually use the exact same skills as a professional interviewer that I do in regular life. So, I'm going to teach you how to interview people, and that's actually going to help you learn how to be better conversationalists. Learn to have a conversation without wasting your time, without getting bored, and, please God, without offending anybody. We've all had really great conversations. We've had them before. We know what it's like. The kind of conversation where you walk away feeling engaged and inspired,
(Risas) (Aplausos) Ahora, yo uso las mismas capacidades como entrevistadora profesional que las que uso en mi vida diaria. Así que, les enseñaré cómo entrevistar a la gente, y eso en realidad va a ayudarles a aprender a ser mejores conversando. Aprender a tener una conversación sin desperdiciar su tiempo, sin aburrirse, y, ¡por Dios!, sin ofender a nadie. Todos hemos tenido grandes conversaciones. Las hemos tenido antes. Sabemos cómo son. El tipo de conversación donde te marchas sintiéndote involucrado e inspirado,
or where you feel like you've made a real connection or you've been perfectly understood. There is no reason why most of your interactions can't be like that. So I have 10 basic rules. I'm going to walk you through all of them, but honestly, if you just choose one of them and master it, you'll already enjoy better conversations. Number one: Don't multitask. And I don't mean just set down your cell phone or your tablet or your car keys or whatever is in your hand. I mean, be present. Be in that moment. Don't think about your argument you had with your boss. Don't think about what you're going to have for dinner. If you want to get out of the conversation, get out of the conversation, but don't be half in it and half out of it. Number two: Don't pontificate. If you want to state your opinion without any opportunity for response or argument or pushback or growth, write a blog. (Laughter) Now, there's a really good reason why I don't allow pundits on my show: Because they're really boring. If they're conservative, they're going to hate Obama and food stamps and abortion. If they're liberal, they're going to hate big banks and oil corporations and Dick Cheney. Totally predictable. And you don't want to be like that. You need to enter every conversation assuming that you have something to learn. The famed therapist M. Scott Peck said that true listening requires a setting aside of oneself. And sometimes that means setting aside your personal opinion. He said that sensing this acceptance, the speaker will become less and less vulnerable and more and more likely to open up the inner recesses of his or her mind to the listener. Again, assume that you have something to learn. Bill Nye: "Everyone you will ever meet knows something that you don't." I put it this way: Everybody is an expert in something. Number three: Use open-ended questions.
o donde sientes que has hecho una conexión real o has entendido perfectamente. No hay razón para que muchas de sus interacciones no puedan ser así. Así que tengo 10 reglas. Y los guiaré a través de ellas. pero honestamente, si solo eligen una de ellas y la dominan, Uds. ya disfrutarán de mejores conversaciones. Número uno: No sean multitareas. Y no solo quiero decir que dejen su móvil, su tablet, las llaves del auto o lo que tengan en las manos. Quiero decir, estén presentes. Estén en "ese" momento. No piensen en la discusión que tuvieron con su jefe. No piensen en lo que van a comer para cenar. Si desean salir de la conversación, abandonen la conversación, pero no estén mitad presente y mitad ausente. Número dos: No sean dogmáticos. si quieren establecer su opinión sin oportunidad a réplica, discusión, aportación o crecimiento, escriban un blog. (Risas) Ahora, hay una buena razón por la que no permito sabiondos en mi show: Porque son realmente aburridos. Si son conservadores, odian a Obama, al programa de comida y al aborto. Si son liberales, odiarán a los bancos, las empresas las petroleras y a Dick Cheney. Totalmente predecibles. Y Uds. no querrán ser así. Uds. deben iniciar una conversación suponiendo que tienen algo que aprender. El afamado terapeuta M. Scott Peck dijo que la escucha sincera requiere de ponerse uno mismo a un lado. Y a veces eso significa dejar a un lado las opiniones personales. Él dijo que al sentir esta aceptación, quien habla estará cada vez menos vulnerable y cada vez más dispuesto a abrir las represiones interiores de su mente al que escucha. Una vez más, supongan que tienen algo que aprender. Bill Nye: "Cada persona que llegues a conocer, sabrá algo que tú no conoces". Yo lo puse en este modo: Todos son expertos en algo. Número tres: Usen preguntas abiertas.
In this case, take a cue from journalists. Start your questions with who, what, when, where, why or how. If you put in a complicated question, you're going to get a simple answer out. If I ask you, "Were you terrified?" you're going to respond to the most powerful word in that sentence, which is "terrified," and the answer is "Yes, I was" or "No, I wasn't." "Were you angry?" "Yes, I was very angry." Let them describe it. They're the ones that know. Try asking them things like, "What was that like?" "How did that feel?" Because then they might have to stop for a moment and think about it, and you're going to get a much more interesting response. Number four: Go with the flow. That means thoughts will come into your mind and you need to let them go out of your mind. We've heard interviews often in which a guest is talking for several minutes and then the host comes back in and asks a question which seems like it comes out of nowhere, or it's already been answered. That means the host probably stopped listening two minutes ago because he thought of this really clever question, and he was just bound and determined to say that. And we do the exact same thing. We're sitting there having a conversation with someone, and then we remember that time that we met Hugh Jackman in a coffee shop. (Laughter) And we stop listening. Stories and ideas are going to come to you. You need to let them come and let them go. Number five: If you don't know, say that you don't know. Now, people on the radio, especially on NPR, are much more aware that they're going on the record, and so they're more careful about what they claim to be an expert in and what they claim to know for sure. Do that. Err on the side of caution. Talk should not be cheap. Number six: Don't equate your experience with theirs. If they're talking about having lost a family member, don't start talking about the time you lost a family member. If they're talking about the trouble they're having at work, don't tell them about how much you hate your job. It's not the same. It is never the same. All experiences are individual. And, more importantly, it is not about you. You don't need to take that moment to prove how amazing you are or how much you've suffered. Somebody asked Stephen Hawking once what his IQ was, and he said, "I have no idea. People who brag about their IQs are losers." (Laughter) Conversations are not a promotional opportunity. Number seven: Try not to repeat yourself. It's condescending, and it's really boring, and we tend to do it a lot. Especially in work conversations or in conversations with our kids, we have a point to make, so we just keep rephrasing it over and over. Don't do that. Number eight: Stay out of the weeds. Frankly, people don't care about the years, the names, the dates, all those details that you're struggling to come up with in your mind. They don't care. What they care about is you. They care about what you're like, what you have in common. So forget the details. Leave them out. Number nine: This is not the last one, but it is the most important one. Listen. I cannot tell you how many really important people have said that listening is perhaps the most, the number one most important skill that you could develop. Buddha said, and I'm paraphrasing, "If your mouth is open, you're not learning." And Calvin Coolidge said, "No man ever listened his way out of a job." (Laughter) Why do we not listen to each other? Number one, we'd rather talk. When I'm talking, I'm in control. I don't have to hear anything I'm not interested in. I'm the center of attention. I can bolster my own identity. But there's another reason: We get distracted. The average person talks at about 225 word per minute, but we can listen at up to 500 words per minute. So our minds are filling in those other 275 words. And look, I know, it takes effort and energy to actually pay attention to someone, but if you can't do that, you're not in a conversation. You're just two people shouting out barely related sentences in the same place. (Laughter) You have to listen to one another.
En este caso, observen a los periodistas. Inicien preguntas con quién, qué, cuándo, dónde, por qué o cómo. Si lo ponen en una pregunta complicada, van a obtener una respuesta simple. Si les pregunto, "¿Se asustaron?". Responderán a la palabra más enérgica en esa oración, la cual es "asustarse", y la respuesta sería Sí o No me asusté. "¿Estabas molesto?". "Sí, lo estaba". Déjalos describirlo. Son los que saben. Intenten preguntar cosas como, "¿Cómo fue eso?". "¿Qué sintieron?". Porque entonces puede que tengan que detenerse un tiempo y pensar en ello, y van a tener una respuesta mucho más interesante. Número cuatro: Sigan el ritmo. Eso significa que vendrán pensamientos a su mente y necesitan permitirles salir de su mente. A menudo, hemos escuchado entrevistas en la que un invitado está hablando por minutos y luego el presentador vuelve y hace una pregunta que parece haber salido de la nada, o que ya ha sido contestada. Allí es probable que él haya dejado de escuchar hace 2 minutos porque pensaba en esta pregunta realmente ingeniosa, y estaba convencido y determinado a decirla. Y nosotros hacemos exactamente lo mismo. Estamos sentados conversando con alguien, y recordamos la vez que encontramos a Hugh Jackman en una cafetería. (Risas) Y dejamos de escuchar. Les vendrán historias e ideas. Deben dejarlas venir y dejarlas ir. Número cinco: Si no saben, digan que no lo saben. Ahora, la gente en la radio, especialmente en NPR es mucho más consciente de que está siendo grabada, y es más prudente sobre los temas en lo que aseguran ser expertos y sobre lo que afirman saber con seguridad. Hagan eso. Pequen de precavidos. La charla no debería ser común. Número seis: No equiparen sus experiencias con las de ellos. Si hablan sobre la perdida de un familiar, no empiecen a hablar de la vez que perdieron un familiar. Si hablan de problemas laborales, no les cuenten cuánto odian su empleo. No es lo mismo. Nunca es lo mismo. Toda experiencia es individual. Y, lo más importante, no es sobre Uds. No necesitan usar ese momento para probar cuán sorprendente son o cuánto han sufrido. Una vez preguntaron a Stephen Hawking cuál era si CI, y él dijo: "Ni idea. El que fanfarronea sobre su CI es un perdedor". (Risas) Las conversaciones no son una oportunidad promocional. Número siete: Procuren no ser repetitivos. Es condescendiente, y es en verdad aburrido, y tendemos a hacerlo mucho. Especialmente en conversaciones de trabajo o con nuestros hijos. Cuando tenemos una idea, la seguimos parafraseando una y otra vez. No hagan eso. Número ocho: Eviten los detalles. Francamente, la gente no está interesada en los años, los nombres, las fechas, todos esos detalles que luchan por traer a su mente. A ellos no les importan. Les importan Uds. les importa cómo son, qué tienen en común. Así que, olviden los detalles. Déjenlos. Número nueve: esta no es la última, pero es la más importante. Escuchen. No puedo decirles cuántas personas importantes han dicho que escuchar tal vez sea la capacidad más importante que podrían desarrollar. Buddha dijo, y estoy parafraseando, "Si tu boca está abierta, no estás aprendiendo". Y Calvin Coolidge dijo: "Nadie ha sido despedido por escuchar demasiado". (Risas) ¿Por qué no escucharse mutuamente? Número uno, nosotros preferimos hablar. Cuando hablo, estoy en control. No tengo que escuchar en lo que no esté interesado. Soy el centro de atención. Puedo reafirmar mi propia identidad. Pero hay otra razón: Que nos distraemos. La persona promedio habla unas 225 palabras por minuto, pero podemos escuchar hasta 500 palabras por minutos. Así que nuestras mentes están llenando esas otras 275 palabras. Y miren, sé que requiere esfuerzo y energía realmente prestar atención a alguien, pero si no pueden hacer eso, no están en una conversación. solo son dos personas gritando oraciones apenas relacionadas en el mismo lugar. (Risas) Tienen que escucharse el uno al otro.
Stephen Covey said it very beautifully. He said, "Most of us don't listen with the intent to understand. We listen with the intent to reply." One more rule, number 10, and it's this one: Be brief. [A good conversation is like a miniskirt; short enough to retain interest, but long enough to cover the subject. -- My Sister] (Laughter) (Applause) All of this boils down to the same basic concept, and it is this one: Be interested in other people. You know, I grew up with a very famous grandfather, and there was kind of a ritual in my home. People would come over to talk to my grandparents, and after they would leave, my mother would come over to us, and she'd say, "Do you know who that was? She was the runner-up to Miss America. He was the mayor of Sacramento. She won a Pulitzer Prize. He's a Russian ballet dancer." And I kind of grew up assuming everyone has some hidden, amazing thing about them. And honestly, I think it's what makes me a better host. I keep my mouth shut as often as I possibly can, I keep my mind open, and I'm always prepared to be amazed, and I'm never disappointed. You do the same thing. Go out, talk to people, listen to people, and, most importantly, be prepared to be amazed. Thanks. (Applause)
Stephen Covey lo dijo muy bien. Dijo: "Muchos de nosotros no escuchamos con la intención de entender. Escuchamos con la intención de responder". Una regla más, número diez, y es esta: Sean breves. [Una buena charla es como una minifalda; corta como para captar interés, pero lo suficientemente larga para cubrir el tema – mi hermana] (Risas) (Aplausos) Todo esto se reduce al mismo concepto básico, y es este: Tengan interés en las personas. Saben, yo crecí con un abuelo muy famoso, y había un tipo de ritual en casa. La gente venía a hablar con mis abuelos, y cuando se iban, venía mi madre y decía: ¿Saben quién era? Era la segunda finalista a Miss America. Él era el alcalde de Sacramento. Ella ganó un Premio Pulitzer. Él es un bailarín de ballet ruso". Y crecí suponiendo que cada uno tiene algo sorprendente y oculto en sí. Y creo que eso es lo que me hace una mejor conductora. Conservo la boca cerrada tanto como pueda, mantengo mi mente abierta, y siempre estoy preparada para sorprenderme, y nunca salgo desilusionada. Uds. hagan lo mismo. Salgan, conversen con la gente, escuchen a la gente, y, más importante, estén preparadas para sorprenderse. Gracias. (Aplausos)